Guide to the Yale College Records Concerning the Five Year Bachelor of Arts Program
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale College records concerning the five year bachelor of arts program
1964-1979
RU 594
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3.75
(3 boxes)
The records consist of memoranda, correspondence, and reports documenting the activities and operations of the Yale College five year bachelor of arts program. Included are materials concerning finances, foreign students and international study, selection committees, post-selection communications, and non-profit organizations.
Yale College (1887- )
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-E (YRG 9-E), Records documenting Yale College offices, programs, and projects.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of memoranda, correspondence, and reports documenting the activities and operations of the Yale College five year bachelor of arts program. Included are materials concerning finances, foreign students and international study, selection committees, post-selection communications, and non-profit organizations.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Bachelor of arts degree; Degrees, Academic; Yale College (1887- ); Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Degrees
- Records of the five year B.A. program, 1965-1973; Accession 1973-A-006
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2054.
  - Accion: Community Action in Latin America, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Accounts
    - Budget, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Payroll distribution register, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Statement of financial policy, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Statement sheets
      - African Studies; Arts and Sciences, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 5 - 6)
      - African Studies; Gifts and Grants, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - African Studies: Library and special use account, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Concilium, African Summer Workshop, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - East African Workshop, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Educational Development, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Foltz, W.J. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Ford Faculty Research, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Ford Foundation, Building and Expendable Fund, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Ford International, Goldsen, J.M., 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Stimson Fund, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - African American Institute, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Agricultural Development Council, Incorporated (ADC), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Annual Reports
    - 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - 1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 22 - 23)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Applicants, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Application material, checklist, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Banking arrangements, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Budget sheets, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Bush Hospital, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Career Advisory Office, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Continuation of program, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Course Programs, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Crossroads, Africa, Inc., 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Dean's Evaluations, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Description of B.A. Program, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Draft Board, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Draft Board, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Evaluation, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Environmental Questions, undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Experiment in International Living, The, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Financial Estimates (Jackie's), 1967-1973 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Foreign Students, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Foreign Students: Post Doctoral Fellows, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Forestry, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Forms: Employer Reference Requests; Preliminary Evaluation; Reference; Selection (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - General, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - General, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Gifts, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Group I
    - General, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - General, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - General - evaluations, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - General, 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - General, 1967-1969 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - General - suggestions, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Letters, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 58 - 60)
  - Group II
    - Confidential references, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - General, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Site visits, 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Year Abroad: materials, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Course schedules, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - General, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 66 - 67)
    - Program letters: addresses and master file, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Group IV
    - General, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - General: application materiaIs, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 70 - 71)
  - Group V
    - General correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 6, Folder 72)
    - General, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 73)
    - Health, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 74)
    - Insurance, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 75)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - General, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Health Program, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - India, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Inquiries, 1965-1970 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Inquiries, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs Correspondence, 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Insurance Program, 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - International Basic Economy Corporation (IBEC), 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 84)
  - Intercultural Education, undated (Box 6, Folder 85)
  - Language tutorials, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 86)
  - Math Program, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - Medical Advisor, Gordon, Martin E., M.D., 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Medical Kits: directions for, undated (Box 7, Folder 89 - 90)
  - Miscellaneous, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - National Defense Foreign Language Fellowship Program, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - News releases, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 93)
  - Peace Corps volunteers, 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 94)
  - Policy, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - Post-selection communications, 1968-1971 (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - Sample letters to applicants, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - Selection Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - Selection Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - Selection Committee, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - Selection materials, undated (Box 7, Folder 101)
  - Southeast Asia (Box 7, Folder 102)
  - Students' suggestions, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 103)
  - Travel information, 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 104)
  - United Nations - UNESCO (Box 8, Folder 105)
  - Venezuela (Box 8, Folder 106)
  - Zambia (Box 8, Folder 107)
  - Audio-Visual Tapes
    - Program and Administrative Procedure, 1967 May 2 (Box 8, Folder 108)
    - "Undergraduates Abroad Testing Classroom Knowledge", undated (Box 8, Folder 109 - 110)
  - Correspondence Richard Baron (Box 9, Folder 112)
  - Correspondence Frank Benest (Box 9, Folder 113)
- Records concerning the background and dissolution of the five year bachelor of arts program, 1964-1979; Accession 1986-A-104
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2015.
  - Papers on the background and dissolution of the Five Year B.A. Program, 1964-1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)